Guide to the Harry W. Frantz Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Harry W. Frantz papers
1913-1971
SC0137
Frantz, Harry W.
2 Linear feet
Collection consists of Frantz's reminiscences of his years as a newspaperman and correspondent for United Press International; some correspondence with friends and colleagues; and copies of articles written by his wife or himself. There is also some material chronicling experiences of the Stanford unit in the American Ambulance Corps (World War I).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Harry W. Frantz, 1971.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Harry Warner Frantz attended Stanford University 1913-1917, 1919; he was a member of the Stanford Ambulance section during World War I (1917-1918). Frantz worked as a correspondent for United Press and contributed to various publications.
Description of the Collection
Collection consists of Frantz's reminiscences of his years as a newspaperman and correspondent for United Press International; some correspondence with friends and colleagues; and copies of articles written by his wife or himself. There is also some material chronicling experiences of the Stanford unit in the American Ambulance Corps (World War I).
Access Terms
Frantz, Harry W.; Taylor, Frank.; Treat, Payson J. (Payson Jackson), 1879-1972; World War, 1914-1918 --Reminiscences.
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1913-1971
  - Clippings from special Stanford edition of Palo Alto Times, collected by HWF, UP, 1941 March (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The University of the World: The Education of an International Reporter, by HWF, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Trans-Atlantic Press Flight: Atlantic Clipper (pamphlet), 1939 June 17-25 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Balkan Tragedy, by David Starr Jordan, sent to HWF, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - History of the American Field Service in France: "Friends of France 1914-1917", volume III by HWF, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Britain's Pinch Hitter," an article by HWF in the Stanford Illustrated Review, 1917 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Herbert Hoover's Goodwill Cruise to Central and South America" by H.W. Hill, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Supplementary file re: Stanford University (correspondence and memorabilia of Administrators, Faculty and Friends) Volume 1, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stanford University supplementary file of correspondence and memorabilia, Volume 2, 1913-1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Random file of miscellaneous memorabilia re: Stanford University, Volume 3, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Ambulance section on the Balkan Front: letters, articles and miscellaneous memorabilia (binder), 1917 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Club of Washington: correspondence and memorabilia (bound scrapbook), Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Volunteers in Sanitary Service of the French Army of the Orient, World War I on the Balkan Front: special articles, letters, maps, documents and miscellaneous memorabilia, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Volunteers in Sanitary Service of the French Army of the Orient, World War I on the Balkan Front: materials from after the war, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Story of an Unknown Reporter" by HWF and miscellaneous articles by HWF and Kathleen Hargrave Frantz, 1950 and undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Trans-Atlantic Press Flight, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Capitol Hill Reporters: insertions in the Congressional Record: an incomplete file of stories originally written for the UP or the Mulberry (Indiana) reporter by HWF and KHF, inserted by congressmen for their historical or biographical value, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "The Flying Pressroom" and cover letter: Charles F. Hughes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "When I think back to San Francisco," written by HWF for the California Historical Society, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellany and memorabilia re: journalistic career and travels, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "How I became an International Correspodent" and correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Kathleen Hargrave Frantz, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "They said to Frantz--," selection from collection of 350 interviews, 1916-1938 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "Reporter writes log of Atlantic Clipper Pioneering Course around Spain", 1939 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - New England vacation: stories by HWF and KHF, and traveler's miscellany, 1941 July (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Rival Universities", Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous articles by HWF, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Spanish newspapers containing articles by HWF, evening bulletins from the USS Utah, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Department of State bulletin, including "Afterthoughts of a Conference Observer" by HWF, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Certificate of Merit for Distinguished Service in International Journalism, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Our Maryland Neighborhood, Christmas 1960" by HWF and KHF (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Articles written by HWF re: Hawaii, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Stories written by HWF at Yellowstone National Park, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Round-About Washington" and biographical items, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - The American Foreign Service journal, 1945 July (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "When I think back to San Francisco", Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Stories by HWF and/or KHF, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The New Year in Serbia, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "Rival Universities", Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "Memories of a California Boyhood", Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Trans-Atlantic Press Flight, Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous articles, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Department of State bulletin, 1945 September 2 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "Frantz in Washington," Alumni Review, 1943 November (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "Haight's Place", Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous articles and stories, Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Stories about post-World War I travels in the Balkans and Stanford, Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous - Cornell, Undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous articles, Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - "Americas" magazine with HWF article, 1955 December (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - "Capitol Hill Reporters", Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - "Campaigns and Campaigners", Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Digesto Economico" with HWF article, 1946 April (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - "Boletin de la Union Panamerica" with HWF article, 1947 April (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Memo to Paul C. Frantz, "Frantz as a Public Speaker", 1937 December 9 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Articles re: Serbia, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Stories by a Stanford undergraduate on and off campus, 1913-1920 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "The World is my Story" and miscellaneous articles, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "The President's Camp on the Rapidan," miscellaneous correspondence and articles, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Photograph of Harry W. Frantz, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence from Stanford friends, 1920-1936 (Box 5, Folder 7)